Jasdeep Singh

SENIOR CLOUD ENGINEER (SECURITY AND PERFORMANCE)

PG5A, Sector 108, Mohali, Punjab, India

□+91 9988638850 | ☑ jasdeep.jogewala@gmail.com | ♠ jasdeep-sinqh.com | ☑ jasdeep | 匝 jasdeep | У jasdeep

CAREER SUMMARY_

With more than 15 years of experience in designing, developing and delivering enterprise software, I take initiative and lead the engineering projects that bring robustness and resiliency to the services offered. My recent work involves security and performance engineering. I have worked on security vulnerability mitigation, migration to cloud infrastructre, performance bug resolution, and introducing concurrency.

EXPERIENCE.

Senior Cloud Engineer Basware

CHANDIGARH, INDIA

April 2021 - Present

- Lead the replacement of an intermediary software to enhance security and visibility of our services for banking institutions, and automate the security certificate renewal to avoid service disruption.
- Envision the design of a secure and faster xml transformation with Saxon XSLT 3.0.
- Plan and mitigate the vulnerabilities reported by Snyk and Nessus on a continuous basis.
- Consolidate secure coding practices and advocate security-by-design culture within the development team as one of the six members of the company wide security guild.
- Achieved performance enhancement by using concurrency and in-memory cache.

Associate Lead Software Engineer

Basware

April 2015 - April 2021

September 2011 - April 2015

CHANDIGARH, INDIA

Successfully developed and deployed secure and high throughput components for an einvoicing solution.

- Planned and mitigated security vulnerabilities reported by Whitesource, Snyk and Nessus on a continuous basis.
- Migrated codebase from SVN to Git repository

Senior Software Engineer

Basware

CHANDIGARH, INDIA Upgraded Peppol libraries (Oxalis and Peppol Silicone) to latest version. Created V1 and V2 Certificates.

Re-designed and migrated existing Servicemix 3.x project to Fuse Servicemix 4.0. This helped us to get rid of legacy (outdated) software.

Kirrt Foundation

CHANDIGARH, INDIA

Lead a digital archiving project that documented artisans and labour

Designed and deployed an AWS hosted web application

Envisioned projects like online viewing room during Covid lockdown

Independent Writer Independent

CHANDIGARH, INDIA

2011 - Present

2010 - 2011

2008 - 2010

2006 - 2008

July 2017 - Present

Languages used: Fountain, Markdown, R Markdown, Leaflet, Python, R, RevealJS

Written dialogues for award winning feature films

Contributed essays and translations to esteemed journals

Presented papers on Cinema and Digital Culture in academic conferences

Net Solutions Web Developer

CHANDIGARH, INDIA Developed and deployed eCommerce web applications using Spring framework.

Successfully implemented payment gateway webservices API.

Technologies Used: Spring, Hibernate, MySQL

Route Guru

New Delhi, India Solely maintained a direction based routing web application written in Struts framework.

Implemented and maintained the web application integration with routing engine written in C++ via JNI.

Technologies Used: GIS, Java, Struts, Spring, PostgreSQL

Software Engineer Fidelity Information Systems

CHANDIGARH, INDIA

Developed and maintained modules for enterprise banking web application using Struts framework.

Technologies Used: Java, Struts, Spring, Oracle

Projects_

Digital archive of protest movment

IIIT

Coordinate with the scientists, engineers and historians from across India to curate a digital archive of the nation wide social movements.

http://indiasocialarchive.iiit.ac.in

Daily news roundup generator and translator

Github 2020 - 2021

CHANDIGARH, INDIA

CHANDIGARH, INDIA

Built a web scraper to fetch news items from leading regional newspapers, and to machine translate the headlines to English using Python, Scrapy, and Google Translation API.

https://github.com/jasdeep/farmers-movement-archive-scraper

Digital archive of artisans

Kirrt 2018 - 2021

1 OF 2

Curated a digital archive of photographs and testimonials of artisans from Punjab.

kirrt.org

Nikola Punjabi localization Github

CHANDIGARH, INDIA Contributed Punjab language localization files to static site generator Nikola

https://github.com/getnikola/nikola/commit/1bcf9968478424eddd579e9b58cffdf298c878af

Ghost4j library switch

CHANDIGARH, INDIA

Github

August 2015 - 2015

Pushed switch to Apache PDFBox from iText library

https://github.com/jasdeep/ghost4j/commit/284c01b277926fce61b5b9ed650595e02a874a0e

2015 - 2015

ORGen code refactoring

Refactored QRGen library code

CHANDIGARH, INDIA

Github 2014 - 2014

SKILLS_

Data HTML, XML, JSON, XSLT, CSS, LaTeX, Markdown, Fountain, AsciiDoc, Leaflet

Databases MySQL, MSSQL, MongoDB

https://github.com/kenglxn/QRGen/pull/42

Frameworks Spring, Spring Boot, MyBatis, Hugo, Blogdown, Wordpress, Nikola

Infrastructure AWS, Docker

Middleware Apache Tomcat, Apache Camel, Apache Active MQ, Amazon Active MQ, IBM MQ, Restful and SOAP Web Services

OS Windows 10, WSL, AWS Linux, Ubuntu, OS X

Programming Java (JEE, JSE), Python, R

Security OWASP, Snyk, White Source, Nessus, Web Services Security and CAS

Tools Git, SVN, Mayen, Ant, Pandoc, Intellij Idea, RStudio, PyCharm, Bamboo, Chef, Jenkins, Splunk, Dynatrace

Writings_

The Mute Fury Bloomsbury

Contributed translation to the book 'Reclaiming the Disabled Subject, Representing Disability in Short Fiction' edited by Someshwar Sati, GJV Prasad, Ritwick Bhattacharjee

Art sans borders: How the pandemic has brought the two Punjabs closer

Scroll.in

· Essay on digital public sphere during the pandemic

The apparatus and the subaltern

Madison, WI, USA

Presented paper "The apparatus and the subaltern: Study of Gurvinder Singh's Annhe Ghorhe Da Daan" at 45th South Asia Conference

Artists in the Internet age

Punjabi University, Patiala, India

Presented paper 'Artists in the Internet age: Works of Teju Cole and others' at the Emerging Contexts of Technology and Culture Conference

CERTIFICATION -

Sun Certified Java Programmer

Global

SUN MICROSYSTEMS

EDUCATION_

B.Tech. Information Technology

Punjab Technical University

BBSBEC, FATEHGARH SAHIB

2001 - 2005

2 OF 2

Worked on the institute web portal project that used Java, XML, XSLT and Apache Cocoon as technology stack